

About

Experienced Area Sales Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the insurance industry. Skilled in Portfolio Management, Negotiation, Financial Risk, Health Insurance, and Business Planning. Strong sales professional graduated from Academia de Studii Economice Bucuresti - Relatii Economice Internationale.

Skills

Attention to detail

Teamwork

Solution oriented

Fast learner

Foreign languages

English $\star\star\star\star\star$ French $\star\star\star\star\star$

Viorel Nicolae

functie

Phone +40722715121

Email viorelnicolae@yahoo.com

Address Bucharest

Experience

Broker Business Development Director

2017 - present

Grawe Romania S.A.

negotiating and concluding contracts with insurance brokers | developing partnerships with insurance brokers | analysis and negotiation of more complex requests for quotation | (conditions, quotations, discounts, commissions)

National Sales Director

2010-2017

FATA Asigurari S.A. – Generali Group

elaboration of the sales strategy | recruitment of branch managers | negotiating and concluding contracts with insurance brokers | development of franchise partnerships | developing the agricultural insurance portfolio through direct | negotiation with large farmers

Regional director

2007-2010

Eureko Romania Insurance Company S.A.

developing the sales network by recruiting agency directors | developing partnerships with insurance brokers | monitoring sales network for achieving the objectives on life | insurance, non-life insurance and the 2nd pension pillar

Project manager

2005-2007

BCR Asigurari S.A.

elaboration of the sales strategy | recruitment of branch managers | negotiating and concluding contracts with insurance brokers | development of franchise partnerships | developing the agricultural insurance portfolio through direct | negotiation with large farmers

President - General Manager

2004-2005

Partener – Broker de asigurare S.A.

Agency Director

2002-2004

Unita S.A.

negotiating and concluding contracts with insurance brokers | recruitment of agency staff and insurance agents | monitoring the activity of the agency in order to achieve the sales objectives

Branch Manager, Area Manager (20 districts)

2001-2002

GRUP AS S.A.

negotiating and concluding contracts with insurance brokers | recruiting branch staff | recruitment of branch managers and agencies in the counties | developing partnerships with brokers in the area | monitoring and direct support to the sales force in case of more complex insurances | direct negotiation of large insurance contracts (conditions, quotations, commissions)



About

Experienced Area Sales Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the insurance industry. Skilled in Portfolio Management, Negotiation, Financial Risk, Health Insurance, and Business Planning. Strong sales professional graduated from Academia de Studii Economice Bucuresti - Relatii Economice Internationale.

Skills

Teamwork

Solution oriented

Fast learner

Attention to detail

Foreign languages

English

French

Branch Manager

ASIROM S.A.

developing partnerships with insurance brokers | recruitment of own sales force (agency directors, insurance inspectors) | training life insurance and non-life insurance | monitoring the activity of the branch to achieve the sales objectives

Life and Group Insurance Department Director 1999-2000 INTERAMERICAN ROMANIA INSURANCE COMPANY S.A.

negotiating and concluding contracts with insurance brokers | recruiting branch staff | recruitment of branch managers and agencies in the counties | developing partnerships with brokers in the area | monitoring and direct support to the sales force in case of more complex insurances | direct negotiation of large insurance contracts (conditions, quotations, commissions)

Economist 1997-1999

The Financial Assistance and Investment Company S.A.

monitoring the development of financing contracts for individuals | negotiation and conclusion of bank deposit contracts | study of the money and capital market and elaboration of syntheses regarding the main indicators

President - General Manager

1997-1999

2000-2001

SOPAS S.A.

Referent, financial analyst, FPAP department head 1994-1997

Private Accumulation and Pensions Fund - Financial Assistance Company and Investments S.A.

public relations | relations with the bank (contracts, account openings, account statements) | negotiating, concluding and monitoring the development of contracts with distribution companies | negotiation and conclusion of bank deposit contracts | coordination of the Private Accumulation Fund and Pensions department

Trainee economist

1994-1994

Romtyre and Rubber S.A.

contacting potential external partners by launching offers through economic advisers of Romanian embassies and consulates abroad | negotiation of export prices (within the limits imposed by management) | negotiation and conclusion of international transport contracts (bill of lading, consignment note) | agreeing, with the external partner, the conditions of payment (letter of credit or documentary collection) and the conditions of delivery of the goods

Education

Economist 1989-1994

Academy of Economic Studies, Faculty of Commerce International economic Relations

Bachelor's Degree: Political Economy, International Trade, Management and Foreign Trade Techniques

Diploma: Foreign exchange and interest rate risk in international trade. Methods and techniques for covering them

Final degree: 9.13

Other courses:

- broker course (broker authorized by the Romanian Commodity
- exchange on the spot, forward, futures markets)
- actuarial seminar life insurance (USAID program)
- investment seminar (USAID program)
- sales techniques courses LIMRA
- claims, reinsurance courses MÜNICH RE, FRANKONA RE